ADITI SEAL

Mobile: +91 7998430339 Email: aditiseal801@gmail.com

DOB: 2nd July, 1997 **Gender**: Female

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Bengali

Location: Bangalore, India



As a System Engineer with over 3 years of experience in the field, I have developed a strong understanding of how to communicate with customers efficiently and effectively. I am confident that my skills and experience in technical as well as business makes me a strong candidate for the role.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Infosys Technologies Pvt Ltd (2021 – Present)

Designation – System Engineer (Software Developer as well as Operations)

Nature of Job – 1st project: Modifying code as per client requirement. 2nd project:

Supporting and managing operations using Service Now, Java and
Interfacing with client.

• Flipkart (April 2021 – August 2021)

Designation – Customer Support Executive (Voice) Nature of Job – Handing customers over calls, emails, chats.

Cognizant Technology Solutions (August 2020 – March 2021)

Designation – Engineer Trainee Nature of Job – Service Desk Support Analyst (Solving customer problems technically over calls, emails, chats)

PROJECTS

Portfolio (Aditi Seal) –

This is my Portfolio website. Used HTML, CSS and JavaScript to build this. **Link** - https://aditi176.github.io/ADITI_SEAL/

Bistro: Dine Here (January 2020) –

It is a website designed for virtual restaurant. Here I have used Html, css and a grid system to make some cards. Also, used JavaScript Lightbox for image gallery.

Link - https://aditi176.github.io/Bistro-Dine-Here/

bYt: Book Your Trip (December 2019 – January 2020)

It is a virtual travel website. Here I have used Html and CSS and media query for the mobile version. Also, used checkbox property to make hamburger menu.

Link - https://aditi176.github.io/bYt-Book-Your-Trip/

Amgen (Client in Cognizant) –

Solved user's problems over calls, emails and chats by using Service Now tool, etc.

- Northwestern mutual (Client in Infosys)
 - 1. First project Modified code as per client's requirement.
 - 2. Second project Working as a part of Operations Team. Interacting with clients, handling Job failures, correcting Data using SQL, managing Incidents in Service Now.

POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

- Handled clients in emergency situations in my previous job.
- Took ownership of any fault from our side while dealing with clients.
- Managed clients in difficult situation.
- Single handedly handled job failures and calls
- Worked as the head-coordinator of my team.
- Organized an event in our college technical fest.

SKILLS

• Business Skills -

- Communication
- Leadership
- Time Management
- Project Management
- Organizational Skills
- Management Problem Solving

• Technical Skills -

- Computer Literacy
- Computer programming (C language, Core Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJs)
- Databases SQL
- ITSM, ServiceNow Management, Customer Support, Customer Handling
- Backend Operations
- Tools
 - Jira
 - Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
 - ServiceNow, Zendesk

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Talking to people
- Writing Diaries
- Listening to melodious songs
- Designing Websites
- Cooking

EDUCATION

• B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (2017 - 2020)

Bengal Institute of Technology, MAKAUT CGPA – 8.37

• Higher Secondary Education in Science (2015 – 2016)

Welland Gouldsmith School, ISC Board

Aggregate % - 77.25

Secondary Education in Science (2014)

Welland Gouldsmith School, ICSE Board Aggregate % - 81.8%